You've learned about
self-attention.
multi-headed attention.
Let's put it all together to
build the transformer network.
In this video,
you'll see how you
can pair the attention
mechanisms you
saw in the previous videos
to build the transformer
architecture.
Starting again with
the sentence 'Jane
visite L'Afrique en septembre'
and its corresponding embedding.
Let's walk through how you can
translate the sentence
from French to English.
I've also added the start of
sentence and end of
sentence tokens here.
Up until this point, for
the sake of simplicity,
I've only been talking about
the embeddings for the
words in the sentence,
but in many sequence-to-sequence
translation tasks,
it will be useful to also add
the start of sentence
or the SOS and
the end of sentence or
the EOS tokens which I
have in this example.
The first step in
the transformer is,
these embeddings get fed into
an encoder block which has a
multi-head attention layer.
This is exactly what you
saw on the last slide,
where you feed in the values Q,
K and V computed from
the embeddings and the weight
matrices W. This layer then
produces a matrix that
can be passed into
a feed-forward neural
network which helps
determine what
interesting features
there are in the sentence.
In the transformer paper,
this encoding block
is repeated n
times and a typical
value for n is six.
After maybe about six
times through this block,
we will then feed
the output of the encoder
into a decoder block.
Let's start building
the decoder block.
The decoders block's job
is to output the
English translation.
The first output will be the
start of sentence token,
which I've already
written down here.
At every step, the
decoder block will
input the first few words,
whatever we've already
generated of the translation.
When we're just getting started,
the only thing we know is that
the translation will start with
a start of sentence token.
The start of sentence
token gets fed in to
this multi-head attention
block and just this one token,
the SOS token,
start of sentence,
is used to compute Q,
K and V for this multi-head
attention block.
This first block's
output is used to
generate the Q matrix
for the next multi-head
attention block
and the output of the
encoder is used to generate
K and V. Here's
a second multi-head attention
block with inputs Q,
K and V as before.
Why is it structured this way?
Maybe here's one piece of
intuition that could help.
The input down here is
what you've translated
of the sentence so far.
This will ask a query to say,
"What of the start
of sentence?".
It will then pull
context from K and V,
which is translated from
the French version
of the sentence to
then try to decide what is
the next word in the
sequence to generate.
To finish the description
of the decoded block,
the multi-head attention block
outputs the values which
are fed to a feed
forward neural network.
This decoder block is also
going to be repeated n
times, maybe six times,
where you take the output,
feed it back to the input,
and have this go through,
say, half a dozen times.
The job of this
neural network is
to predict the next
word in the sentence.
Hopefully, it will decide
that the first word
in the English
translation is Jane.
What we do is then feed
Jane to the input as well.
Now, the next query comes from
SOS and Jane and it says,
well, given Jane, what is the
most appropriate next word?
Let's find the right key
and the right value,
then lets us generate the
most appropriate next word,
which hopefully will
generate visite.
Then running this neural
network again generates Africa.
Then we feed Africa
back into the input.
Hopefully it then generates
in and then September,
and with this input,
hopefully it
generates the end of
sentence token and
then we're done.
These encoder and
decoder blocks,
and how they're combined
to perform a
sequence to sequence
translation tasks
are the main ideas
behind the transformer
architecture.
In this case, you
saw how you can
translate an input sentence into
a sentence in another language
to gain some intuition
about how attention
in neural networks can be combined
to allow simultaneous
computation.
But beyond these main ideas,
there are a few extra bells
and whistles to transformers.
Let me briefly step through
these extra bells and
whistles that makes
the transformer network
work even better.
The first of these is positional
encoding of the input.
If you recall the self
attention equations,
there's nothing that indicates
the position of a word.
Is this word the first
word in the sentence,
in the middle, the last
word in the sentence?
But the position within
a sentence can be
extremely important
to translation.
The way you encode
the position of elements
in the input is that you
use a combination of these
sine and cosine equations.
Let's say, for example,
that your word embedding is
a vector with four values.
In this case, the dimension D of
the word embedding is 4,
so x^(1), x^(2),
x^(3), let's say those are
four dimensional vectors.
In this example, we're
going to then create
a positional embedding vector of
the same dimension,
also four dimensional.
I'm going to call this
positional embedding p^(1),
let's say for the
position embedding
of the first word Jane.
In this equation below, pos,
position denotes the numerical
position of the word.
For the word Jane,
pos = 1,
and i over here refers to
the different
dimensions of encoding.
This first element
corresponds to i = 0.
This element i = 0,
i =1, i = 1.
These are the
variables pos and i,
they go into these
equations down below.
Where pos is the
position of a word,
i goes from 0 to 1,
and d = 4,
is the dimension of this vector.
What the position encoding
does with the sine and
cosine is create a unique
positional encoding vector.
One of these vectors that
is unique for each word,
the vector p^(3) that encodes
the position of l'Afrique,
the third word will be a set
of four values that'll be
different than the
four values used in
code position of the
first word of Jane.
This is what the sine and
cosine occurs look like.
Is i = 0,
i = 0,
i = 1, i =1.
Because you have these terms and
denominator you end up with i =
0 will have some sinusoid
curve that looks like this,
and i =0 will be
the matched cosine.
90 degrees out of face and i
=1 will end up with a
lower frequency sinusoid,
and i =1 gives you a
matched cosine curve.
For T1, for position 1,
you read off values at
this position to fill in
those four values there.
Whereas for a different word
at a different position,
maybe this is now three
on the horizontal axis,
you read off a different
set of values.
Notice these first two
values may be very
similar because they're
roughly at the same height.
But by using these multiple
sines and cosines,
looking across all four values,
P3 will be a different
vector than P1.
The positional
encoding, P1j is added
directly to X1 to the input this
way so that each of the
word vectors is also
influenced or colored with
where in the sentence
the word appears.
The output of the
encoding block contains
contextual semantic embedding
and positional
encoding information.
The output of the
embedding layer is then D,
which in this case four
by the maximum length of
sequence, your model can take.
The outputs of all these
layers are also of this shape.
In addition to adding
these position encodings
to the embeddings,
you'd also pass them through
the network with
residual connections.
These residual connections
are similar to
those you previously
see in the resnet.
Their purpose in this
case is to pass along
positional information through
the entire architecture.
In addition to
positional encoding,
the transformer
network also uses
a layer very similar
to a batch norm.
Their purpose in this
case is to pass along
positional information
into position encoding.
The transformer also uses
a layer add norm that is
very similar to the
batch norm layer
that you're already
familiar with.
For the purpose of this video,
don't worry about
the differences.
Think of it as
playing a role very
similar to the batch norm.
This helps speed up learning
and this batch norm like layer,
this add & norm layer is
repeated throughout
this architecture.
Finally, for the output
of the decoder block,
there's actually
also a linear and
then a soft max layer to
predict the next word
one word at a time.
In case you read the literature
on the transformer network,
you may also hear
something called
the mask multi-head attention,
which I'm going to
draw and over here.
Mask multi-head attention is
important only during
the training process
where you're using a
dataset of correct
French to English translations
to train your transformer.
Previously, we
stepped through how
the transformer performs
prediction one word at the time,
but how does it train?
Let's say your dataset has a
correct French to
English translation.
Jane visite l'Afrique on September,
and Jane visits
Africa in September.
When training, you
have access to
the entire correct
English translation,
the correct output,
and the correct input
and because you have the
full correct output,
you don't actually
have to generate
the words one at a
time during training.
Instead, what masking does
is it blocks out
the last part of
the sentence to mimic what
the network will need to do
at test time or
during prediction.
In other words, all that
mask multi -head
attention does is it
repeatedly pretends
that the network had
perfectly translated,
say the first few
words and hides
the remaining words
to see if given
a perfect first part
of the translation,
whether the new
network can predict
the next word in the
sequence accurately.
That's a summary of the
transform architecture.
Since the paper attention
is all you need came out,
there have been many other
iterations of this
model such as BERT
or DistilBERT which
you get to explore
yourself this week.
That was it. I know there
was a lot of details,
but now you have a good sense of
all of the major building blocks
of the transformer network.
When you see this in this
week's program exercise,
playing around with the code
there will help you to build
even deeper intuition about
how to make this work
for your applications.